

Laurence de Jong

linkedin.com/in/laurencedejong · github.com/ldej

I'm a Dutch software engineer with over 10 years of experience in developing web applications. I

provide technical leadership for small teams. My favourite language is Go, though I've had a lot of fun in Python before. You can wake me up to talk about decentralization.

Experience

CodeNotary • Senior Backend Software Engineer | Remote • Apr 2022 - Feb 2023

go microservices immudb postgres nats solr supply chain security

- Added multi-tenancy, refactored the application in order to create automated tests
- Integrated Solr search and added a message queue to offload processing. Standardized APIs using OpenAPI, designed a SBOM processing pipeline

Xebia · Senior Consultant | Gurgaon, India · Feb 2020 - Nov 2021

- Gave talks on Google Cloud, Go Architecture, IPFS and at the bi-weekly knowledge exchange sessions.
- Participated as judge at the Hackathon of the technical university in Dehradun.
- Participated in the hiring process by interviewing potential new hires.

Novamedia / Postcode Lotteries • Senior Software Engineer | Amsterdam, Netherlands (remote) • Apr 2021 - Nov 2021

typescript nodejs express react graphql aws amplify scrum

- Developed the Deal or No Deal game for Postcode Lotteries using AWS Amplify.
- Implemented NodeJS/Express endpoints for Lambdas that use TypeScript models generated from GraphQL definitions.
- Developed a back-end system for generating input for lottery draws.

Action • Senior Software Engineer | Zwaagdijk, Netherlands (remote) • Feb 2021 - May 2021

go gcp cloud run gcp spanner gcp cloud build docker scrum

- Created the online webshop for Action. Implemented the product catalog, ordering system and e-mails. Created the backoffice management system for products and orders.
- Implemented solutions for integration with external systems for content management and finances.
- Configured CI/CD with Cloud Build and created extensive unit and integration tests.

IDFC First Bank • Senior Software Engineer | Gurgaon, India (remote) • Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

go microservices kubernetes gocd oracledb mulesoft scrum

- Designed and integrated a fraud detection system.
- Created a new microservice which includes authentication, authorization, logging, monitoring, tracing, database migrations, unit tests and integration tests.
- Configured GoCD to automatically build and test.

Unifyed • Senior Software Engineer | Gurgaon, India (remote) • Mar 2020 - Jul 2020

mongodb nginx microservices jenkins scrum

- Implemented performance optimizations in a number of ways including hosting static files.
- Planned and upgraded their running MongoDB PSA clusters from version 3.4 to 4.2. Upgraded MongoDB drivers in all
 microservices and resolved compatibility issues.
- Implemented automated building and deployment of the platform.

Xebia · Consultant Software Engineer | Hilversum, The Netherlands · May 2017 - Jan 2020

- Gave talks on blockchain and IPFS at the bi-weekly knowledge exchange sessions. Participated in bi-monthly innovation days.
- Interviewed potential new hires.
- Co-organized DjangoGirls Amsterdam 2019.

Duxxie • Platform Developer | Utrecht, The Netherlands • Jun 2018 - Jan 2020

go gcp app engine event-sourcing algolia circleci scrum

- Tech lead for the development of the platform.
- Migration of App Engine from runtime v1 to v2. Worked with and expanded the custom event-sourcing system. Implemented a catalogue search. Introduced a CMS for the product catalogue.
- Onboard external suppliers on the platform and integration of their systems.

Nextail • Full-Stack Developer | Amsterdam, The Netherlands • Jun 2017 - May 2018

go qcp app engine algolia circleci vue.js scrum

- Launch of a multi-tenant e-commerce platform.
- Incorporate legacy IBM WebSphere e-commerce backend. Implement product catalogue search using Algolia.
- Leading development team with remote workers.

Contracts11 · Software Engineer | Groningen, The Netherlands · Feb 2015 - Nov 2016

python falcon livescript mithril aws (ec2, ecs, s3) nats docker rancher elk stack alert-manager smart contracts

IOT LoRaWaN

- Research and develop a language to describe business processes. Generate models, database schemas, front-end and back-end functionality based on the descriptions.
- Developed a back office system for a liquor trader that could process price lists in various formats. The system could show price trends across the market and advise on selling and buying.
- DevOps: Set up Jenkins, Postgres with automated migrations, monitoring, logging and alerting using ELK stack. Set up Docker orchestration using Rancher.

Paylogic • Software Developer | Groningen, The Netherlands • Sep 2011 - Sep 2014

python django sqlalchemy django pytest

- Research and select a Continuous Integration tool. Set up Jenkins including a build farm.
- Set up automated database generation for local development. Set up automated testing using pytest. Automated database migrations using Alembic. Analyzed and solved database performance issues.
- Developed functionality for the ticketing platform.

Ytec • Junior Software Developer | Groningen, The Netherlands • Nov 2009 - Jul 2010

python django jQuery

• Building web shops using Python and Django. Building the front-end using JS/jQuery.

Volunteer

Coach @ DjangoGirls

- Organised: 03-02-2018 Amsterdam
- Coach in Groningen on 25-05-2019, 03-11-2018, 04-11-2017, 20-05-2017, 12-11-2016, 23-04-2016, 19-09-2015, 21-03-2015, 22-11-2014
- Coach in Novi Sad, Serbia on 24-10-2015

Education

Computing Science \cdot Master of Science (MSc) \cdot Software Engineering & Distributed Systems

2012-09 - 2015-09, University of Groningen

Technische Informatica · Bachelor of Applied Science (B.A.Sc.) · Embedded Software Engineering

2007-09 - 2012-07, Hanzehogeschool Groningen